If you've been watching AI for the last
few years and feel like you're
constantly falling behind, this video is
going to change how you think about all
of it. I'm going to show you why almost
every AI course, every prompt training,
every type of package or thing or
training that's going on out there is
teaching the wrong layer. I want to
teach you the layer that almost nobody
else is teaching. The one that survives
the next model update, every framework
depreciation, every bigger email or
chain that says we're sunsetting this
product. the layer that all the big guys
know about but they're not talking to
you about. And I'm gonna show you what
30,000 people in our community are
already doing with it. My name is Jake
Van Clee. I'm founder of Adoba. And for
the last 3 years of my life, 15 hours a
day, I have been learning and I'm about
to share what I have learned throughout
all of this process in this new AI world
and what the next decade is going to
look like. Perhaps you learned prompting
six months ago or a year ago ago and it
worked for a while and then the models
got better and now most of that became
irrelevant. Or perhaps you built some
fancy agentic framework or a new startup
tool and it worked but then the next API
update or the next cloud update the
whole thing broke or became irrelevant
again. Or even worse, maybe you took a
course paid for a couple courses and
half of what was in those courses was
outdated in less than 90 days. I mean
think about it. You hop on Twitter,
LinkedIn, all of these Instagram and
YouTube and somebody is posting a new
workflow, a new tool, a new you have to
try this or check out this feature. This
changes everything and you haven't seen
it yet. So now you feel like you're
falling more behind and it just keeps
piling up and you don't know what to
learn. But here's the thing that
nobody's telling you. You're not falling
behind because AI is moving too fast. AI
isn't moving that fast. Almost 10 years
ago, the attention is all you need paper
from Google came out. That's what all
these transformer models and language
models are built off. Basically, that's
been 10 years of patterns that have
existed and are the same patterns today.
And even further, these same patterns,
these software fundamentals have existed
for so much when personal computers were
first being built when the internet was
being built with mobile phones all the
way back to the 1950s. We've seen this
movie play out before. And there's
fundamentals that have existed the whole
time that you can learn. Is you're not
behind because you're slow. You're
behind because you're learning the wrong
layer. And until somebody teaches you
which layer to be at, what that layer
even looks like, you're going to keep
feeling like this. And you're going to
keep chasing and you're going to keep
starting over. And every time something
updates, you're going to feel behind.
We can change that with a simple
process. I want to show you how to slow
down, how to stop and think about what's
going to be useful in 10 years, not just
two months from now. And I really want
to say that and explain that through two
main stories. What I'm going to teach
you right now didn't come from a lab,
PhD program, or me sitting there and
running studies and ethics programs. Not
hating on those, but experience teaches
a lot. And this story comes from me
being in the Marine Corps for over eight
years and then another three years of
being frustrated by gatekeeping and
people telling me and using fancy words
to hide something simple. So in the
Marine Corps I was working on
cryptographic systems. I was working on
F-18s, F-35s, the avionics behind them.
These were zero defect envir
certifications. You can have engineers
and PhDs. You can have experts, people
with high rank telling you the way to do
something, but at the end of the day,
they're hearing that from someone else.
You can actually cut 90% of that process
out and still come to the same outcome
that you needed. Now, yes, there is
still important times you should listen
to that experience. There is times that
that matters. But for most situations,
for almost everything, in order to make
real progress, you need to think about
the fundamentals and ignore everything
else. And living in that environment,
living in how the world was supposed to
work, but then seeing how it actually
worked was the first crack into how I
thought about expertise. The f the final
crumble happened when I was actually
getting my master's degree. And it's
actually how I ended up building my
methodologies and processes that I'm
working with today. It's ICM. The second
story is how I built the methodology
that thousands of people are using
today. And I want to be honest with you
about this. This is not the version most
founders would tell. I didn't sit down
with a design methodology. I didn't have
a Eureka or whiteboard moment. It was
really all the way back in 2022 when I
started messing around with language
models around my research and and
academic. I was telling my professors
that I wanted to use them to essentially
help me write articles or at least see
what would happen if they did write
these articles, these these academic
stages. What was missing? I had to
organize everything. every output I
needed to track and I put it into files
so I could copy and paste it over and I
kept creating organization structure for
these AI just to track what it was doing
and understand it. That was it. That was
the start. And over time I I realized
that that process for something that
wasn't even coding was git. That was
version control. It was more than just a
basic process. It was something that
could be used to scale my thought. I
stopped using language models just for
software coding and building, but looked
at for outcomebased work. How could I
use these systems to create animations
or to organize things completely
differently for my writing and language
work? And I had to organize everything
completely different. I had to be able
to set it up for my chaotic creative
environments where I would open sessions
randomly without losing context. I
needed to be able to separate files or
route the agent to specific places. But
I kept working through this whole chaos
of my own work. I built my own agentic
flows. I tested them. I used other
people's frameworks like lane chain and
semantic kernel and all of these things.
But I kept coming back to the basic
files and systems because I could get to
the outcome faster. And more
importantly, I could see and control the
outcome as it was happening. And I
realized that that process worked and I
know I needed to formalize it. So, I
wrote a paper, but I didn't write it to
formalize it. And I wrote it spitefully
because I knew that these researchers,
these PhDs that I was working with every
day would never take it seriously if I
didn't write it in the form that they
were used to, in the way that they like
to gatekeep knowledge. And don't get me
wrong, I love academia, but I literally
had PhDs tell me to my face that
language models and AI were useless.
Meanwhile, I was actively building real
tools, things that worked with them,
doing things that was never possible
before, getting actual outcomes, and
they were telling me my tools didn't
work while I was using them. And the
critics aside, they had good reason
because other people, other AI gurus and
instructors were teaching features, and
they still are. They're just teaching
basic prompts or frameworks and they're
giving AI a bad name because their
courses are shallow or the outcomes
weren't really real. They weren't
focusing on actual realworld
implementation. So I just got angry. But
let me just give this methodology away.
Let me actually show what's working,
share it with everyone, let them use it.
And then I could use that as proof to
say look this is the way. This is where
you get real outcomes. I didn't want to
gateep it. I wanted to prove it. And in
all of this, I did some research of the
past. Where else did people have to deal
with these sort of problems, especially
in the computation field? And it brought
me back to a wonderful, most brilliant
woman named Grace Hoppers. They wouldn't
use this. They told her that it wouldn't
work. She had a working compiler in her
hand and they wouldn't touch it. I'm not
telling you this because AI is going to
be this distant thing that's going to
work one day in the future. I'm telling
you this because it works right now
and I've been I have something in my
hand that is working and I've been
making it work for 3 years straight with
over 30,000 other people actually using
it and getting outcomes from it. That's
the story. That's where all of this
methodology and process comes from. But
I keep using the key words. I'm still
gatekeeping even in this video and I
don't mean to because it's hard to
describe it so quickly. So, let me tell
you what the actual methodology is
because this is really the part that
changes everything. Every AI course
you've ever taken, every framework
you've learned, every tutorial you've
watched has been teaching you agents or
agentic flows. It's been telling you,
oh, you got to use NAND or Langchain or
Autogen or all these multi- aent agentic
systems. You have to have these
orchestrations. And that's great. Some
of them can work, but that's still the
surface level. That's not getting you
set up for the next decade. Agents,
frameworks, all of these things can be
absorbed. They can break. They change
with model updates. A lot of them can be
outdated in 90 days because of how
things are adopting. They're not moving
fast because those systems are out those
systems are not becoming obsolete
because AI is moving too fast. They're
becoming obsolete because people are
building at the wrong abstraction layer.
And every 90 days, you pretty much have
to start over because you're not
learning the right layer. The layer
underneath all of that is what I am
teaching. It's what my interpretable,
it's what my M focuses on. Interpretable
context methodology. And the tagline is
the simplest way I can say it. Folders
over agents. This is me not saying that
you shouldn't build intense
infrastructure. It is me saying that the
organization and context structures are
more important than all of it. The way
you structure information, the way you
organize folders, the way you route
between context layers, that's the
architecture. The agent is just the
thing using the architecture. When you
build a folder system, a file setup that
works, it doesn't care what model you
use. It doesn't care what framework or
AI you have. It doesn't care what's hot
this month. If cloud updates or OpenAI
updates something or version 6 comes
around, it works. The architecture, the
architecture and context will always the
architecture and context survives. It
can abstract infinitely. When Claude
updated, my workflows kept working. When
GPT 5.5 dropped, my workflows and
systems kept working and got better.
When the next model lands in a few
months, my systems will work better.
There is no replacing it because it is
the fundamental of how these systems
work. And realistically, my methodology
works on five layers of content.
Identity at the top, then routing, then
stage contract, followed by reference
material, then working into working
artifacts. And you can organize all
sorts of databases and folder bases and
scripts around this. And any AI agent
can come in and read everything. That's
the whole framework. It looks simple. It
can be broken down simply because it is.
And there's a reason nobody else is
teaching this. It doesn't really look
that impressive once you start doing it.
There's no demo video where I show you a
sexy agent multi-swarm system doing your
job for you. There's no flashy framework
name. There's no library to import. It's
just folders and the discipline of
organiz through the lens of a world of
AI. It is me taking what worked in the
1970s and has continued to work and work
better every year since and simply
adapting it to this new set of
abstraction, this new set of AI tool.
And you see, most educators can't sell
that. Either they don't know how to
articulate it or they need the
spectacle. They need the latest tool.
They need the the new shiny thing
because that's what gets them clicks and
gets them views because that's all they
care about. I'm not selling a spectacle.
I'm trying to give you the layer
underneath. If you spend 3 months
learning my processes and systems in 5
years, you'll still be able to get value
from it. You're still using it. If you
spend three months learning the latest
agent framework, nine months, most of
it's going to be either useless,
absorbed, or you're going to be
relearning a whole new version of it.
And that's it. That's the difference.
That's my whole pitch. And I could give
you proof. I could spend the next five
minutes telling you all the enterprise
companies I've been working with,
whether it's Pacific Life or KPMG or the
UK government. We've done it all. I've
worked with them and gotten real
outcomes, real outputs, and real
reports. You can go check it online. But
honestly, I don't care about
recommendations or big companies or
anything like this. The real proof comes
from my community. We have 30,000 people
in my community at the time of this
recording. And most of them got there
within 2 months. 2 months. And 30,000
people join to learn about what we're
building. They're not paying to be
there. Most of them are all on the free
tier. Maybe 1,500 to 2,000 of them are
paying for more time with me. Everyone
else is free and every single day all of
them are posting real win. They're
getting token reduction. They're cutting
API costs and hour costs and structural
issues by sometimes 80 90 95% because
they finally understand how to structure
context, how to structure thinking in
software. These are real outcomes.
people getting jobs, people getting
raises, people getting promoted, people
closing new clients, and people building
products that work because they're
saving hours and hours of week and
finally have a system that doesn't
break. They finally have a system that
they can understand. And they're not
posting about this in the community
because I'm paying them or to justify a
purchase. Most of them haven't bought
anything. They're posting because it
works and they want to share what
they're proud of working. That to me is
the proof I trust. I care about that and
that's what you should look at more than
anything out of all the stuff I do. And
they're doing that not because AI is
magic, not because they're keeping up
with all the new updates, but because
their structures were right, because
they had the context routed correctly,
because the architecture, the data, the
thinking survives transitions from one
model to the next or are amplified by
them. When CTO's or software engineers
come asking for time with me, it's not
because they saw a sales page. It's not
because I'm sending cold emails. I don't
have any automations for messages. I
don't have any automations for crazy
emails hitting everyone else. It's
because they're seeing outcomes from
stuff I'm giving away for free. It's
because their friend had shown them an
actual system they've built and they are
coming to me wanting to know more,
wanting to know how it works. That's
word of mouth from people who have
nothing to gain by talking about it.
Unfortunately, and fortunately, I've had
a massive influx of people asking to
learn more. And I've been wanting to
solve this problem, as I said, of this
knowledge gap. There's such a huge
knowledge gap. And I know it can be
solved with the right systems, with the
right learning at the right layer. So,
I'm going to be launching something
called the Lysum. This isn't a course.
This isn't uh some weird thing where I'm
going to be telling you how to make
money online. This is learning. This is
knowledge. This is schooling. This is
knowledge packaged into real work. I'm
going to be creating three cohorts. Each
one is going to be focusing on a
specific nuance of my method. Technical,
business, and creator. Those are the
three cohorts. Same methodology for each
one, but different applications of the
methodology. If you're a developer or an
engineer or technical founder, you might
want to go into the technical cohort.
You will build an actual production
system, learn about these methodologies.
You're going to think about API
integrations, agentic architecture,
thinking through the lens of my
methodology, the underlying processes.
This is where we get into the deep weed,
the technical systems, and you end up
with a tool or a system you ship. If
you're in ops or management or you're
running a business or looking at doing
consulting, then my business cohort will
be learning similar things as the
technical except we're spending more
time on how to direct technical people.
What happens when you have a team of
people using these tools and models? How
do you get ROI on these implementations?
Your capstone project is going to be
focused around creating the systems of a
company. What does an AI native company
even look like? You're going to have
that automated spec, that process, that
structure before you leave. And if
you're a creator, you're an artist,
you're a marketer, or maybe even just an
educator or solo operator, then the
creator fund is for you. I'm all about
show your work. And sometimes it's hard
to show your work in a world where
everything is filled with yapping and
talking heads. Well, here we're going to
focus on the methodology, but we're
going to build content pipelines. We're
going to build oneperson systems that
have allowed me to get millions and
millions of views across all of my
social medias with just myself and an
audience scaling infrastructure. You're
going to look at a capstone project that
focuses on content production to run
with or without you to scale who you
are, not replace it. Again, each of
these are focusing and teaching the same
methodology, the same processes just
with slightly different examples,
different time waiting and different
capstone. Now, you might be wondering,
okay, well, if it's not a course, if
it's not this annoying asynchronous
thing, what is it is? These are going to
be real live sessions over fourth
trainings work with me and an entire
team I am putting behind of highly
educated instructors to help support you
in and out of the class. You're going to
get all of the recordings for lifetime.
You can pull the transcripts, give them
to your AI, re look back at them, listen
to those questions again. You're going
to get written curriculums. You're
getting private cohort Discords. You're
even going to have a certification by
the end of this that's from my official
company, Adoba, that is training
enterprise people and helping them hire
people. So, that training assessment
certification is actually useful and
something you can put on your resume.
You're going to get lifetime access to
my community through VIP going to help
you. I'm not just teaching you and
dropping you off. I am trying to make an
impact on the world through knowledge,
through sharing that process and
building with people. I want to put my
money where my mouth is and work with
you. And here's the thing that no one
else is doing. I'm going to guarantee
you that you walk away with a working
product, a working company or process.
Not a just a certificate to hang on the
wall, not a course completion badge, not
a oo I hope you learn and utilize this.
A real functioning thing that has
outcome and output that you built during
the program.
And my guarantee is that if you don't, I
will personally sit and work with you. I
will bring my team on and finish it
until you have something that works. I
will ensure you don't walk away
empty-handed. I don't see any other
programs offering that promise because
they can't. I actually use this with
companies. I build these things. We know
this methodology works and it works for
hundreds of enterprise people as well as
thousands of people in my community. and
it will work for you, too. Now, you
might be wondering, "Oh, well, how much
does it cost all this?" Don't worry
about any of that. I'm just having a
wait list right now. I'm trying to work
with everyone, see what we're doing.
We're looking at scholarships, getting
people in for free, all of that stuff.
We're trying to open up a weight list
right now. That's all we're doing. And I
need your help just to get in.
Right now, we're just opening the wait
list for public enrollment. If you join
the wait list, you're going to be the
first to see any sort of pricing
updates. You're going to be the first to
see start dates. You're going to be able
to give feedback on when and how you
want to join and you're going to get
access to all of this stuff before we
open it to the public. There's only, and
here's the important part, my time is
limited and there's only so many people
I can teach. So, we're limiting it to
100 per cohort. That is 300 seats in
total. Mind you, in my community, we
have over 430 people active any given
minute. So, when those seats are gone,
they're gone. If you know this is for
you, join the weight list now. And I
want to leave you
and all the pricings and getting in and
call to actions, all that stuff out of
the way. I just want to leave you with
this one concept. Grace Hopper, the
brilliant scientist I told you about
earlier, was working
had a working thing in her hand. She had
something that could change the way
people work. She had something that was
valuable and people constantly told her
it was useless.
I have a working methodology in my hand.
You have working ideas in your head.
30,000 people are using my methodology.
Fortune 500 companies and getting real
output out of it. People may tell you
the same thing they always tell people
who try to build something. They might
tell you it doesn't work. They're going
to tell you it's useless. You can listen
to them or you can come build with us.
We'll build together. Folders over
agents, layers over libraries,
methodologies over tools. Then we dive
into all those things I just said after
the next cohort fills up soon. Pick your
spot, get on the wait list, and I'll see
you inside. Until next time friends,
happy learning.